<item>
	<title>Using titanpad.com and Drop Box for collaborative learning and coding.</title>
	<link>http://vgoff.posterous.com/using-titanpadcom-and-drop-box-for-collaborat</link>
	<pubDate>Tue Aug 31 01:23:00 -0700 2010</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victor Goff]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="collaboration"><![CDATA[collaboration]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="process"><![CDATA[process]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="tools"><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vgoff.posterous.com/using-titanpadcom-and-drop-box-for-collaborat</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you are looking for tools to help with distance learning and teaching, you may consider two tools that I have been using recently.</p>
<p>One of the tools I have been using is titanpad.com which allows for a custom domain, if you want to use their hosting. &nbsp;The tool that is used, though, is really a modified EtherPad, FOSS software that is available via github.com, if you would like to use it for your own domain.</p>
<p>The other tool that I have been using for the file side is Dropbox.com. &nbsp;It has some nice features, even for the 'free' option. &nbsp;The two that I use it for the purpose of this article is the immediate updates, and the sharing.</p>
<p>What follows is a description of the benefits I have noted using these two tools in a few interactive training sessions.</p>
<p>I conduct remote training in a few areas of software programming, and have noticed using titanpad.com and dropbox (when the student agrees to use that as a solution) that my 45-60 minute tutorial gets cut down to an average of 20 - 35 minutes. &nbsp;The thing about the training is that it is designed to be most affective when it can be done interactively. &nbsp;This means "hands on" for the code, and "hands on" for the discussion. &nbsp;It isn't a static presentation, and though I limit how far the creativity goes, the solutions do vary, and I do encourage that.<p /> These two tools allow me to not worry about the mechanics of our interaction, and it encourages us to work on the discussion together, as well as the program we are working on. &nbsp;It lets us work on the "same program' interactively, and get the changes "quick enough" without more than just saving the file, as changes are made. &nbsp;With some procedures set for saving output from the file runs to a 'results.txt' file on Dropbox, we can see exactly the results produced, and other information that is generated from our program. This means:</p>
<ul>
<li>No copy and paste</li>
<li>No e-mailing files back and forth</li>
<li>No downloading files from the internet via:  
<ul>
<li>a browser</li>
<li>ftp command</li>
<li>etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, working on the same file in this way presents the potential of making changes to the same lines, etc. &nbsp;But with the constant communication flow, and coordination, even working on the same file is a breeze.</p>
<p>Not having to copy and paste code all over the place, and not having to look at separate results (by concatenating a results.txt file with your tests and runs) we get 'quick enough' feedback on what we are working on. We didn't have to move a file, we simply hit the "Save Button" and the other person gets notification that the file has been modified. &nbsp;A&nbsp;good editor will let you know when the file you&nbsp;have open is modified, and allow you to reload pretty simply. &nbsp;Dropbox seems to be pretty fast at synchronizing the content of your 'shared' directory.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For the discussion part, it is typed on&nbsp;<a href="titanpad.com" title="TitanPad" target="_blank">titanpad.com</a>&nbsp;and allows us to all have our fingers in a discussions document, seeing live-time comments being made. &nbsp;This also allows us to record our decisions, and allows us to review the document as it was produced at a later time, allowing us to see the journey to our result. &nbsp;Titanpad also has a sidebar chat available for quick comments to be made. &nbsp;Unlike other tools online, it doesn't disrupt the typist(s) in the main document, and allows quick feed back to be taken into consideration as you are typing, without being too obtrusive. &nbsp;The chat is available and recorded along side the document, the document itself is playable using a "Time Slider". &nbsp;The document is also available to download as HTML, PDF, Word, etc. &nbsp;You can even save different revisions.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Titanpad could benefit from having some syntax highlighting, I think. But it really isn't necessary. &nbsp;The author indicator is color based, and unobtrusive, but informative. &nbsp;The editors you are probably using probably have syntax highlighting anyway.</p>
<p>In summary, for me, it seems to speed up&nbsp;collaborative coding in a learning environment, it requires only the download and install for the Dropbox daemon, is web-centric for the conversation, and should be simple enough for most programming students, and versatile enough for advanced teams trying to quickly work on some pretty complex code.</p>
<p>If you would like a Dropbox account, you can click on <a href="http://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTEwNjU0MTY5OQ" title="Referral Link" target="_blank">this link</a>.</p>
<p>What tools do you use for pair programming or for direct interaction, live-time, remote learning sessions?</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[If you are looking for tools to help with distance learning and teaching, you may consider two tools that I have been using recently. One of the tools I have been using is titanpad.com which allows for a custom domain, if you want to use their hos...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Tue Aug 31 01:23:00 -0700 2010</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>using-titanpadcom-and-drop-box-for-collaborat</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
